<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Central Florida Real Estate Video Blog with The Rodriguez Team</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Rodriguez Team is to be your best resource for Central Florida real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Rodriguez Team, your professional Central Florida Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 14:47:42 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 14:47:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Most Common Forms of Property Ownership</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Iq2GU7q3Z3o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;re reviewing the most common forms of property ownership in our area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What are the most common forms of property ownership in Central Florida?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the answer, let’s start with a &lt;strong&gt;quick reminder: Title equals ownership&lt;/strong&gt;. Title can be held in two different ways, the first of which being as “severalty” (meaning it’s owned by an independent person or entity), and the second being as a “concurrent estate” (meaning it’s owned by more than one person at a given time). So, now that we’re clear on those definitions, let’s move on to the two most common forms of ownership for both individual owners and multiparty owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common forms of ownership for an individual in Central Florida are “fee simple” and “leasehold” ownership. &lt;strong&gt;Fee simple ownership is when an individual owns a piece of real estate outright&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning they own all the land, dwelling, and air rights to a property. Fee simple tenure is also considered indefinite, wherein the owner has the right to sell or dispose of the property as they please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leasehold ownership is basically where a parcel of land and the building on that land have different owners&lt;/strong&gt;. So, in essence, the owner of the land is leasing the rights of the property to the tenant. Leasehold ownership is also referred to as “tenancy for years” because it generally lasts for a specific period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Title can be held in two different ways: 'severalty' or 'concurrent estate.'%20http://localhost:4000/the-most-common-forms-of-property-ownership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Title can be held in two different ways: ‘severalty’ or ‘concurrent estate.’”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things get a bit more complicated when two or more owners take title to a single piece of real property. In fact, there are several different kinds of multiparty ownership. The two main types of multiparty ownership in Central Florida are “tenants in common” and “joint tenants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenants in common refers to instances in which each owner retains separate rights over their share of the property&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, let’s say two people own the same commercial building together. The deed specifies that Person A owns 60% and Person B owns 40%. Person A can sell or give away their 60% without telling Person B because the sale would not affect Person B’s ownership of his 40% share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;if these co-owners were joint tenants, then each owner would have equal rights over the entire property&lt;/strong&gt;. In other words, Person A could not sell a share of the property without Person B’s consent. Furthermore, if either co-owner were to die, the survivor would automatically take full possession of the property, a scenario which is also known as “joint tenants with rights of survivorship.” If you’re married, it’s called “tenant by the entireties,” which is basically the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this message helped clarify some property-related jargon you’ve heard being thrown around. If you have any questions about ownership or are interested in soon becoming a property owner yourself, reach out to us by phone or email anytime. We’re always happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-most-common-forms-of-property-ownership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-most-common-forms-of-property-ownership.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wishing You the Best This Holiday Season</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gCEyAuoZ_OA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rodriguez Team wants to extend its sincere thanks to you for your continued support.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The holiday season has officially arrived. We hope you enjoy this wonderful time of year and make some fantastic memories. &lt;strong&gt;We wanted to take a moment to thank you for your continued support&lt;/strong&gt;. We love helping people make their real estate dreams come true, so thank you for working with us and supporting our business. The future is full of possibilities, and we hope you are as excited for this upcoming year as we are. Here’s to making 2021 our best year yet!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wishing-you-the-best-this-holiday-season.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/wishing-you-the-best-this-holiday-season.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Are Homestead Exemptions so Important?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CvZBzTeYn1Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are three main reasons why filing for a homestead exemption is so important.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today’s topic is especially important for anyone who bought a home this year: What is the homestead tax exemption, and why is it important?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s determine what Florida property taxes actually do. Well, they help your city and local officials raise funds. They pay for police, firefighters, schools, roads, etc. Every November, the tax bills come out based on the assessed value of your property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s talk about the homestead exemption, what that is, and how it benefits you. First of all, your homestead property is considered your primary residence. Therefore, &lt;strong&gt;you can only homestead one property at a time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you're a veteran, disabled veteran, or senior citizen, you get additional exemptions.%20http://localhost:4000/why-are-homestead-exemptions-so-important.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re a veteran, disabled veteran, or senior citizen, you get additional exemptions.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first benefit of the homestead exemption is that you can get a discount on your property tax assessed value. Your tax assessed value is the amount the government can tax you on and is slightly less than your home’s market value. The general rule of thumb is that it’s about 85% of your market value. So for a $100,000 property, your tax assessed value is about $85,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off the top, &lt;strong&gt;in the state of Florida, you get a $25,000 discount if you file as a single person and a $50,000 discount if you’re married&lt;/strong&gt;. So if you have a $50,000 exemption, you reduce that from the $85,000 to get your tax assessed value, and the government can only tax you on $35,000 of that. Also, if you’re a veteran, disabled veteran, or senior citizen, you get additional exemptions. Check with your local property appraiser’s office to see what exemptions you’re eligible for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second benefit of the homestead exemption is creditor protection. If for any reason you are sued civilly, they can’t touch your homestead or the equity on that property. So creditor protection is very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third benefit is the 3% cap. In terms of tax assessed value, &lt;strong&gt;there is a ceiling on appreciation&lt;/strong&gt;; even in areas that have appreciated more than 3%, the maximum they can assess you is 3% per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope this shines a little bit of light on the subject. If you have any further questions, give us a call at (407) 519-0627. We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-are-homestead-exemptions-so-important.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-are-homestead-exemptions-so-important.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Rodriguez Team Wishes You a Happy Thanksgiving</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fvwvtrieg24?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick message of thanks to you in the spirit of the season.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The 2020 holiday season has officially begun, and we hope you are as excited about it as we are. I know it’s been a crazy year, and even so, I feel like there’s so much to be thankful for. We’ve met some truly incredible people this year and have had the privilege and honor of being able to assist many of you in accomplishing your real estate dreams. &lt;strong&gt;Without all of you and your support, we wouldn’t be where we are today&lt;/strong&gt;. We hope you enjoy your Thanksgiving with your family and your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if you have any real estate-related questions, please feel free to reach out to us because we’re here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-rodriguez-team-wishes-you-a-happy-thanksgiving.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-rodriguez-team-wishes-you-a-happy-thanksgiving.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are the Benefits of a Buyer Consultation?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yq0RHClKevw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why are buyer consultations so important to first-time homebuyers?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today I want to address a question that often comes up, especially for new buyers: Why are buyer consultations important? There are three primary reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. They provide a detailed needs analysis&lt;/strong&gt;. One of the first things we do during our buyer consultations is the needs analysis, which allows us to cater specifically to our clients’ needs and wants. We’ll discuss things like motivation, time frame, location, and home criteria. Using that information, we’ll be able to better search for homes on your behalf and only send you listings that meet your criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. They educate you on the current market and let you review the buying process&lt;/strong&gt;. The market is constantly moving, so when it’s time for you to buy, we want to make sure you have a great understanding of what’s happening based on up-to-date market statistics, not just our opinions. Since this may be your first time buying a home, we’ll also review the buying process with you and address any questions or concerns you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You’ll become familiar with your agent&lt;/strong&gt;. You’re preparing to purchase one of the largest assets of your life, and you should feel comfortable and confident that your agent will get the job done for you. Not every agent works the same, so this gives you the opportunity to interview your agent and make sure they have the skills, experience, and qualifications you’re looking for. There are no bad buyers—only bad Realtors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying a home, reach out to us. It’ll be our pleasure to walk you through the process to make sure your home buying experience is a great one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-benefits-of-a-buyer-consultation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-benefits-of-a-buyer-consultation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is a New Foreclosure Crisis Looming on the Horizon?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uIKZxS1NUvg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are my thoughts about a possible foreclosure crisis on the horizon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today I want to talk to you about a foreclosure crisis that might be looming on the horizon, and what it could mean for you. I’m sure you know how &lt;strong&gt;the pandemic and lockdowns have hurt the economy&lt;/strong&gt;. Many people have lost jobs or had their hours cut significantly. As a result, they are struggling to make regular mortgage payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably also heard about various forbearance programs. These are temporary private and government programs that allow mortgage borrowers to postpone or even reduce their monthly mortgage payments. As it stands, 3.7 million borrowers are in mortgage forbearance programs. That’s about 7% of all active mortgages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these folks just hit the six-month mark of mortgage forbearance. The big question is what will happen in another six months when the maximum term for these forbearance programs comes to an end? That brings me to the possibility of a foreclosure crisis. Indeed, many people will still not be able to make their mortgage payments as forbearance programs run out. &lt;strong&gt;Unfortunately, some will be forced into foreclosure&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I’m not expecting a scenario like 2008. The difference comes down to current sky-high home prices and record-low mortgage rates. These unique circumstances mean that most homeowners have equity in their homes right now. In fact, home equity for homeowners with a mortgage rose 6.6% annually in the second quarter of this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This rise in equity means homeowners have options, even if they are struggling to make payments. In other words, they can put their homes on the market and sell them rather than lose them to foreclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=About 7% of all active mortgages are in forbearance.%20http://localhost:4000/is-a-new-foreclosure-crisis-looming-on-the-horizon.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“About 7% of all active mortgages are in forbearance.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean for you? Well, &lt;strong&gt;the current real estate market is severely short on its supply of homes&lt;/strong&gt;. Homes are selling very quickly and at record prices simply because demand is so much higher than supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if we don’t see a foreclosure crisis in the coming months (and I do not believe we will), there is likely to be a flood of new homes for sale on the market. It’s likely to put a chill on home price growth or even reverse it. We will enter a more balanced market, where buyers have more of a say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bring this up in case you have been thinking about selling soon but are still on the fence. The current moment might be golden. The lack of supply right now means you could sell quickly and for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, whether you’re buying or selling, give us a call or send a quick email today. We have our fingers on the pulse of the Central Florida real estate market, and we can help you make the right decision for your specific circumstances. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-a-new-foreclosure-crisis-looming-on-the-horizon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/is-a-new-foreclosure-crisis-looming-on-the-horizon.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Credit Score and Down Payment Are Needed to Buy a Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K62nCh-E7FE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what to know about credit score and down payment requirements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today we’re joined by our good friend &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://movement.com/lo/trey-delgreco/&quot;&gt;Trey DelGreco with Movement Mortgage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; to answer a two-part question: What is the minimum down payment and credit score needed to obtain a loan these days?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a question Trey hears all the time and the right answer depends on your situation. Typically, &lt;strong&gt;the higher your credit score is, the less of a down payment you’ll need&lt;/strong&gt;, while a lower score will require a higher down payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are down-payment assistance programs out there.%20http://localhost:4000/what-credit-score-and-down-payment-are-needed-to-buy-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are down-payment assistance programs out there.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The target minimum for most loans is a 620 credit score&lt;/strong&gt;. You can get a conventional or FHA loan with this score, but you might need more of a down payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have a big down payment or any down payment, there are options for you. There are down-payment assistance programs as well as 0% financing programs available. &lt;strong&gt;Just be ready to have a higher credit score if you apply for one of those programs&lt;/strong&gt;. They typically require at least a 640 score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for Trey, give him a call at (407) 240-7063. If you have any other real estate-related questions for us, feel free to contact us via phone or email anytime. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-credit-score-and-down-payment-are-needed-to-buy-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-credit-score-and-down-payment-are-needed-to-buy-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Upgrades Are Worth It?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qxuXOF3mrQ8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is how I suggest you spend your money on home improvements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One question we’ve been hearing a lot recently is, “What can I do to improve my home so I can get top dollar in the resale market?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One example comes from a client who recently sold their home in Kissimmee. She needed to paint, change some flooring, freshen up landscaping, and basically reset the home for the next owner. With our help and that of our staging consultant, we were able to guide her through this process and suggest simple improvements that ultimately got the property sold with multiple offers and above market value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re sharing tips that will ensure your home improvements make money for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Neutralize the color palette&lt;/strong&gt;. It is always best to neutralize any bold or unique colors, and make more neutral color selections for the walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Shore up curb appeal&lt;/strong&gt;. Make sure the curb appeal of your home is attractive to any buyer driving up. That could mean changing a front door, painting, or restaining. Those are very simple things to do. Trimming trees away from your rooftop is a great idea as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It is always best to neutralize any bold or unique colors.%20http://localhost:4000/what-upgrades-are-worth-it.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It is always best to neutralize any bold or unique colors.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Focus on flooring and the kitchen&lt;/strong&gt;. It may be as simple as replacing old carpet to give more of a refreshed look or possibly putting in faux wood tile, laminate, or vinyl. We have great contacts if you ever need to talk to someone about it. Freshen up the kitchen cabinetry as well. That could be as easy as getting some different fronts for the cabinetry so you don’t have to replace the full box, or painting and adding some updated hardware to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Let the natural light shine&lt;/strong&gt;. Make sure all the light bulbs match, have warm light, and aren’t too bright. If you have any solar screens on your windows, take those off to let the light in, and make sure you get the windows cleaned, or do it yourself. An easy thing is to get Fabuloso, water, and a mop, and go to town on the inside and outside of your windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are just some of the things we recommend to get your home ready for the market. If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-upgrades-are-worth-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-upgrades-are-worth-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do I Make My Offer Stand Out to Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/A3ZKYQPImKU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are the three keys to standing out in a multiple-offer situation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lately, we’ve had several buyers ask us, “What can we do to make our offer look stronger?” In today’s highly competitive market where we’re seeing more and more multiple-offer situations, this question is only natural. If you find yourself competing against other buyers for the same property, remember these three tips for making your offer stand out to sellers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Write your contingencies to be as brief as you feel comfortable&lt;/strong&gt;, or eliminate them altogether. For example, shortening your inspection contingency from 15 to seven days shows the seller you’ll be quick to order your inspections, meaning they’re only at risk of having their property off the market for seven days instead of 15. Alternatively, if you’re receiving a loan, you may reduce or remove your appraisal contingency since you can order your appraisal during your inspection contingency period. For example, if you have 15 days to do your inspections and you remove your appraisal contingency altogether, just arrange for your appraisal to be done in that 15-day window. Since the inspection contingency is considered a ‘free look,’ you don’t need to give a reason for backing out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Increase your escrow deposit amount&lt;/strong&gt;. We advise our buyers to offer a minimum deposit of 2% of the home’s purchase price. This deposit is made in good faith to show the sellers you are serious about purchasing their property. A large part of our job as real estate professionals is protecting a buyer’s deposit, so the more money you feel comfortable with depositing, the stronger your offer appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Never underestimate the power of a determined buyer and an experienced agent.%20http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-make-my-offer-stand-out-to-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Never underestimate the power of a determined buyer and an experienced agent.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Go above asking price and appraised value&lt;/strong&gt;. In our current market, this approach is becoming more common. If you happen to find that perfect 10-out-of-10 dream home, there will most likely be multiple offers on it, and you may have to pay above asking price. We recently competed against 13 other offers on a home in Winter Garden! The home was a flawless fit for our buyers, and they wanted us to do whatever it took to get their offer accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home was priced at $400,000, so we decided to offer $405,000, and pay $1,000 above appraised value up to $405,000. In other words, if the property only appraised for $400,000, our buyers communicated to the seller that they would still be willing to pay an additional $1,000 out of pocket. Since no other buyers offered to pay above appraised value, our buyers got the house!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how fierce the competition is out there, you can never underestimate the power of a determined buyer and an experienced agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about this topic, or if you hear of anyone looking to make a move that we can help, feel free to give us a call or send a text to 407-519-0627. As always, make sure you like, share, comment, and subscribe to our channel—hit that notification button so you never miss a video!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-make-my-offer-stand-out-to-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-make-my-offer-stand-out-to-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do I Do If I’ve Inherited a Property?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5HoH3mNq74I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve inherited a property, these four steps will help you deal with it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you inherit a property, you may not know what to do with it. These are the first four steps to follow if you inherit real estate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Meet with a probate attorney&lt;/strong&gt;. An attorney can help you find out who has assumed the various rights and responsibilities associated with the property so you can get a full picture of what you’ve inherited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Have the property inspected&lt;/strong&gt;. We recommend treating the inherited property as you would a real estate purchase. Before you buy a property, you have to have it inspected, so do the same when you inherit a property. Knowing what shape it’s in will help you with later decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Find out whether there are any obligations attached&lt;/strong&gt;. Ideally, the inherited property will be paid off, but that’s not always the case. Contact your trusted local real estate professional to see whether there are any ongoing or imminent obligations such as payment of taxes, landlord-related obligations, or mortgages. Some loans are required to be paid immediately if the borrower passes away; if the beneficiary wants to keep the property, they’ll need to consider whether they can pay it off or have the credit and financial ability to refinance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Decide whether to sell or keep the property&lt;/strong&gt;. Once you have all the other information we’ve covered, you’ll be ready to decide what to do with the property. It’s important to determine the property’s current market value for both renting and selling. Consider both options because inheriting a property can give you a massive boost in building long-term wealth. It may be tempting to sell it at first, but consider the long-term cash flow potential of renting it out. Contact your trusted real estate agent to talk through your options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We recommend treating the inherited property as you would a real estate purchase.%20http://localhost:4000/what-do-i-do-if-ive-inherited-a-property.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We recommend treating the inherited property as you would a real estate purchase.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have further questions about inheriting property or real estate in general, contact us via phone or email or leave a comment. We would love to be your chosen local Realtors. Remember: Your goals are our priority.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-do-i-do-if-ive-inherited-a-property.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-do-i-do-if-ive-inherited-a-property.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
