<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Central Florida Real Estate Video Blog with The Rodriguez Team</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Rodriguez Team is to be your best resource for Central Florida real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Rodriguez Team, your professional Central Florida Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:22:52 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:22:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Keller Williams’ “Ready to Sell” Program</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sgb08ZmkBJo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;We’re so excited to be offering this great program from KW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you hoping to get top dollar for your home sale but don’t have the money to fix it up, don’t know any contractors, and don’t know where to start? We have a solution for you! This program is a complete game-changer and is going to be able to help a lot of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, I’m excited to announce that our team is officially certified for Keller Williams’ Ready to Sell program which allows you to repair or renovate your home before putting it on the market with $0 out of pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Ready to Sell program gives you 2 different options:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Apply for 0% financing&lt;/strong&gt; for the cost of the renovation through one of our preferred partners. Once the property sells, you’ll be able to pay that back with $0 upfront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Access the equity you already have in your home&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have enough equity, we’ll be able to leverage it for the cost of the renovation and pay the contractor back once your home sells with $0 upfront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key phrase to note here is “$0 upfront.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We manage the entire construction process with our own contractors.%20http://localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-keller-williams-ready-to-sell-program.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We manage the entire construction process with our own contractors.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This money can be used for small projects such as paint, pressure washing, landscaping, and flooring, or it can be used for bigger projects like full kitchen and bathroom renovations. The goal is to figure out the minimum money we need to spend in order to get the maximum return on your investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The great thing is that there’s no cost, no pressure, and absolutely no obligation to move forward with the project once we present our estimates for the repairs&lt;/strong&gt;. If you do decide to move forward, the whole construction process is taken off your hands and we manage the entire project with our own contractors and trades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again this program is hassle-free and requires $0 upfront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your home is ready, we market it aggressively, negotiate all offers, and ultimately sell your house with the best terms and most money possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the program, the market, or otherwise, make sure you give us a call at (407) 519-0627 or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-keller-williams-ready-to-sell-program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-keller-williams-ready-to-sell-program.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How the Foreclosure Process Works</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zn1JYDWZ4Cw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Today I’m sharing a quick walk-through of the typical foreclosure process in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about the foreclosure process: what it is, how long it takes, and important things to know. First of all, &lt;strong&gt;every foreclosure timeline can be different&lt;/strong&gt;. Today’s information is meant to be general and will be a good, average timeline here in Florida when it comes to foreclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that happens is that you’ll get behind on your mortgage payments. People ask all the time, “If I get a month behind on my house payment, are they going to foreclose?” The answer to that question is generally no, but of course, there are exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have tons and tons of equity in your house and the mortgage company thinks they can foreclose and get all their money back, they will do it sooner rather than later. If you’re upside down on your mortgage, meaning you owe more on your home than what it’s worth, then you might be able to get further past due on your house before they ever look to foreclose on it. I’ve heard stories of people being over two years past due on their house before foreclosure ever took place, and I’ve also heard the horror stories of somebody being only 30 to 60 days past due, so it all depends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You have 20 days to respond after receiving your letter of foreclosure.%20http://localhost:4000/how-the-foreclosure-process-works.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You have 20 days to respond after receiving your letter of foreclosure.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;the mortgage company will file the foreclosure lawsuit, and you’ll be notified of a foreclosure hearing date&lt;/strong&gt;. That foreclosure hearing date will take place in front of a magistrate or lay judge, in the county you’re located in, about 30 days after you receive the letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have 20 days to respond and either admit or deny the allegations. You’re not required to attend the hearing, but you can sometimes go in and explain your situation, let them know you’re working on a modification of the mortgage, and that you’re trying to sell the property. At times, &lt;strong&gt;the magistrate may be willing to give you an extension or a second hearing date&lt;/strong&gt;. This doesn’t happen all the time though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the second hearing, they’re not going to give you another continuance. After the hearing, if the mortgage company believes they can foreclose and the Final Judgement of Foreclosure is approved, they will enter a Foreclosure Sale date within 35 to 120 days. On the date of the sale, interested buyers can bid on the property at the county courthouse, and the highest bidder becomes the new owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the state of Florida, &lt;strong&gt;there’s a statutory right of redemption which gives the previous borrower 10 days to buy back the property&lt;/strong&gt; before the certificate of title is filed. After those 10 days, that ship has sailed, and there’s nothing you can do to get your house back. This would be your final chance to file for bankruptcy if you choose to do so. The time from your initial letter of foreclosure to your actual foreclosure sale date is typically about eight to 14 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a foreclosure attorney, but I can get you connected if you need one or just have any questions. If you’re faced with foreclosure and want to know your options, give us a call or send us an email today. We would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-the-foreclosure-process-works.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-the-foreclosure-process-works.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Should Know Before Selling Off-Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/84GpeWLepvA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s what you should know before selling your home off-market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of selling your home and mention this fact to a neighbor, coworker, friend, family member, etc, there’s a good chance one of them knows someone looking to buy a home who’s having a bad time with current market conditions. The question for you then becomes: Should I sell my home off-market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most honest answer I can give you is that it depends.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s no ‘yes’ or ‘no’ answer to that question because it depends on your situation and goals. That said, there are two costs to keep in mind when selling your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is the agent’s commission. This is usually the biggest cost of selling a home, and if you sell off-market, you don’t have to pay it, which can lead to huge savings. However, since the buyer is buying directly from you, they’re probably expecting to pay less for your home, so the monetary difference could end up being a wash—and you’re still stuck handling the transaction and doing all of the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You could be leaving thousands of dollars on the table by not testing the free market.%20http://localhost:4000/what-you-should-know-before-selling-off-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You could be leaving thousands of dollars on the table by not testing the free market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second cost comes in the form of not allowing the market to dictate the price. Even if you look at all of your neighbors’ comparable sales, there’s no way to test what buyers are willing to pay for a home in this market without putting that home on the market. Right now we’re seeing buyers paying well over asking price for homes with little to no contingencies in their offers. One of the biggest benefits of the free market is being able to determine the most someone is willing to pay for your property. You could be leaving thousands of dollars on the table by not testing the free market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a potential off-market seller, I recommend talking to an unbiased agent&lt;/strong&gt; so they can provide specific information about your market and offer some insight as to what your home might sell for on the open market. They’ll also explain your options if you’d still rather sell off-market. Ultimately, you want to reach out to someone who’ll make sure you’re doing what’s in your best interest and will help you accomplish your real estate goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-should-know-before-selling-off-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-you-should-know-before-selling-off-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Buy First, Sell First, or Do Both at the Same Time?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/M_9asTWxwCk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are your three options when you want to buy and sell a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you sell your home and buy a home at the same time? Here are the three ways to go about this and some strategies for each method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.  Buy first.&lt;/strong&gt; You can buy your house first and then sell. By buying first, you get to enjoy the search without the pressure of having to sell your house. You also won’t need interim housing, and you can prepare your current home for sale as you move out and transition into the next one. One of the risks that you do face is potentially having to pay multiple mortgages and not having the equity of the first house to put down on the next house. We will give you an estimate, but we won’t know exactly how much until the home sells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buying and selling at the same time is certainly doable.%20http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-first-sell-first-or-do-both-at-the-same-time.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buying and selling at the same time is certainly doable.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Sell first.&lt;/strong&gt; You can also sell first and then buy. If you choose to sell first, the good thing is that you know exactly how much equity you’ll be able to put down for your down payment. You won’t have two mortgages to worry about either. On the flip side, you may have to plan for interim housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Concurrent sale.&lt;/strong&gt; A simultaneous closing of both properties. Buying and selling at the same time is certainly doable. We’ve had the opportunity to help a number of clients with this in the past, and it just takes good planning, communication, and some clever negotiating. We’ve created a system to help streamline the process and are happy to share that with you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you attempt any of these options, there are some things you need to do first.&lt;/strong&gt; The most important thing is to review your finances and get pre-approved by a lender. You’ll know exactly how much you can afford and whether or not you have to sell your current home in order to buy the next property. This comes up with a lot of our clients who are either upsizing or downsizing locally, as well as clients who are moving from outside of the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate questions we can answer or know of anyone who’s making a move or thinking about investing in real estate that might need our help, give us a call at (407) 519-0627.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-first-sell-first-or-do-both-at-the-same-time.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-first-sell-first-or-do-both-at-the-same-time.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Make These Mistakes as a Homebuyer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wOnTaPQs0CE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are five mistakes you must avoid as a first-time homebuyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a first-time homebuyer, here are five mistakes you must avoid during the purchase process to ensure your transaction runs as smoothly as possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Not properly preparing your home insurance&lt;/strong&gt;. Your lender will require you to get an adequate home insurance policy before closing on your loan. If you forget to secure one or your policy start date doesn’t align with your closing date, your transaction could get off schedule. In many cases, the home just isn’t insurable. This might happen if the previous owner made an insurance claim for some sort of high-risk condition, like mold or severe water damage. It also might happen if they have an open claim that hasn’t been closed yet. The best thing to do is stay ahead of these mishaps and look for home insurance as soon as you go under contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Not preparing for a low appraisal&lt;/strong&gt;. Not many homeowners have a good understanding of appraisals. If your appraisal comes in lower than your offer, it could send things to the drawing board. You may have to pay the difference, renegotiate with the seller, or back out of the deal entirely if both parties can’t come to terms. Your lender won’t cover more than the appraised value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since homes in our area are appreciating quicker, low appraisals are happening more and more often. In certain cases, a low appraisal can benefit a homebuyer because it ensures they’re not paying more than what the house is worth. On the other hand, in this insane seller’s market where every home seems to be getting 20 offers, it might be worth it to pay above the home’s appraised value if you think it’s the right home for you. Sometimes offering $1,000 over the appraised value is enough to make your offer stand out and get accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Lowering your credit before your lender closes the loan&lt;/strong&gt;. Many lenders will recheck your credit just before closing on the loan, which can be a problem if you’ve already made a major purchase or applied for additional loans or credit cards. Fortunately, this is an easy mistake to avoid. Just keep a tight rein on your spending in the weeks leading up to the purchase and save big-ticket purchases (e.g., a new car) until after you close on your loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure you hire a great agent who can walk you through the home-buying process, answer all your questions, and make the purchase a great experience.%20http://localhost:4000/dont-make-these-mistakes-as-a-homebuyer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure you hire a great agent who can walk you through the home-buying process, answer all your questions, and make the purchase a great experience.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Making errors in your homebuyer loan documents&lt;/strong&gt;. If you spot an issue in your final closing disclosure or your name is misspelled on your loan documents, your closing could be delayed and your lender would have to append the paperwork before it can be signed and notarized. That’s why it’s critical for you to review all documents you receive right away so if there are any errors, you can report them to your loan officer as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Having problematic walk-throughs&lt;/strong&gt;. Before you close on your loan, you’ll have the opportunity to perform a final walk-through of the house to ensure any repairs you’ve requested have been done, the homeowner has cleared everything out, and that the home itself has been maintained and is in the same condition as it was when you made your offer. If that isn’t the scenario you walk into, you’ll have to work with your agent to resolve this issue. They may need to ask for additional credits at closing to cover any additional repairs or schedule a cleaning or trash removal if the house is in disarray. The best thing you can do is ensure your agent works closely with the listing agent so that all repairs have been made and there’s proof of that before the final walk-through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want your purchase to stay on track, so it’s important to be proactive leading up to closing. In addition to these tips, make sure you hire a great agent who can walk you through the home-buying process, answer all your questions, and make the purchase a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-make-these-mistakes-as-a-homebuyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/dont-make-these-mistakes-as-a-homebuyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Restrictions Mean Increased Mortgage Costs on Second Homes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ya9f6thAjRA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;New restrictions could make buying a second home much more costly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates and fees on investment properties and vacation homes have been skyrocketing, and there are a few reasons why. On March 10, Fannie Mae placed tighter restrictions on the number of second home/investment property mortgages that lenders can buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fannie Mae is one of the big banks that purchases loans after they close. In the past, around 14% of Fannie Mae loans were allowed to be used for second homes and investment properties. Due to the aforementioned restrictions, that percentage has been slashed in half to around 7%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many lenders depend on Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac when selling their loans, so these rules are putting a lot of strain on mortgage companies&lt;/strong&gt;. After the 7% cap is reached, these banks won’t be able to purchase any more loans. This also puts more risk on the lenders, as they could be stuck with loans that nobody wants to buy. However, they’re avoiding it by shifting the risk to buyers through higher loan costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These new rules may also encourage lenders to be even more selective when it comes to working with buyers.%20http://localhost:4000/new-restrictions-mean-increased-mortgage-costs-on-second-homes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These new rules may also encourage lenders to be even more selective when it comes to working with buyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been reported that PennyMac, one of the largest loan servicing companies for these types of loans, has already added an additional 2.25% charge on loans for non-primary resident applicants. &lt;strong&gt;In other words, it costs more to get a mortgage on second homes or investment properties&lt;/strong&gt;. This also includes people with down payments of 25% or more, and those who pay less face an additional 5% cost. For example, if you wanted to borrow $300,000 for an investment property and put 20% down, you could face an additional $15,000 charge or a higher rate to compensate for the fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though criteria like credit score, debt-to-income ratio, and cash reserves aren’t affected, it’d still be wise to save up additional money for the down payment on a second home. This can help cover fees and rates that are likely to be much higher on loans that have less than 20% to 25% down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These new rules may also encourage lenders to be even more selective when it comes to working with buyers. Even if you are selected, you can still expect to pay a higher rate—even when you’re in good financial shape—when buying a second home. The window of opportunity may be closing, but you can lower costs by increasing your credit score, paying debt, and saving up a sizable down payment. The strength of your application will matter more than ever, so these factors also help in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like to know what this means for you, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/new-restrictions-mean-increased-mortgage-costs-on-second-homes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/new-restrictions-mean-increased-mortgage-costs-on-second-homes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Comparing Our Traditional Listings and Guaranteed Offers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tTJnKpFVJC8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s some more great info on our guaranteed offer program.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since we launched our &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://centralfloridarealestateblog.com/guaranteed-offer/&quot;&gt;guaranteed offer program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, we’ve been getting a lot of questions like, “What’s the difference between your traditional listing program and a guaranteed offer program?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest difference between the two programs is &lt;strong&gt;a matter of convenience.&lt;/strong&gt; With our guaranteed offer program, you can basically bypass the traditional home sale process and sell on your timeline. Once we submit your property to our investors, we can have multiple cash offers in as little as seven days. This means you can close quickly, save the time and money of preparing the home, forgo all showings and open houses, choose your closing date, and move on your timeline. Another great thing is that we’ll still be here to help you negotiate the best offer and terms so you’re not dealing with the investors on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Diverse home-selling needs call for diverse solutions.%20http://localhost:4000/comparing-our-traditional-listings-and-guaranteed-offers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Diverse home-selling needs call for diverse solutions.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;our traditional listing program will be the way for our seller clients &lt;em&gt;to make the most money possible&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by putting their home on the open market. This involves a little more work by default, but we do our best to make it hassle-free for our sellers. We follow a 14-step marketing plan to help maximize your property’s value, we follow up with all showings, and we ultimately negotiate the best offer and terms so you can walk away with the most money possible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there’s really no wrong choice. At the end of the day, it’s a matter of convenience. We understand that every seller’s situation is unique, so we want to offer two great solutions to help them reach the next stage of their lives. As always, feel free to reach out if you have questions about this or any other real estate topic. We’re happy to be a resource for you and assist with whatever buying, selling, or investing needs you may have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comparing-our-traditional-listings-and-guaranteed-offers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comparing-our-traditional-listings-and-guaranteed-offers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Is Good Faith Money Important?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jJbQ0KFbYlY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is good faith money and why is it important? Find out here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What is good faith money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a buyer’s offer on a home is accepted, they’ll include a deposit called the earnest money deposit with a deadline on when the funds will be deposited to the escrow agent. Normally, the escrow agent is also the one who will handle the closing. The earnest money deposit is supposed to show good faith that the buyer is serious about purchasing the home, and it goes toward their down payment and closing cost at settlement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In central Florida, &lt;strong&gt;the normal earnest money amount is between 1% and 3% of the sales price&lt;/strong&gt;, though it can vary. If there are multiple offers on the home, a buyer might want to increase their earnest money deposit to make their offer look stronger to the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The earnest money deposit shows good faith that the buyer is serious about purchasing the home.%20http://localhost:4000/why-is-good-faith-money-important.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The earnest money deposit shows good faith that the buyer is serious about purchasing the home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the buyer were to back out of the contract, both parties have to agree to this decision before the funds are released to either party. If the buyer has a home inspection contingency, finance or appraisal contingency, or another contingency, they can use them as options to void the contract and they will get their earnest money deposit back. Once the contingencies have expired, the earnest money deposit is at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate questions or needs, or if you know of anyone we can help, reach out to us anytime. We hope to hear from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-is-good-faith-money-important.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-is-good-faith-money-important.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When an Appraisal &amp; Contract Price Don’t Match</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8pOyOYkTJNM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a seller, here&amp;rsquo;s what you can do if your home&amp;rsquo;s appraisal comes in low.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What happens if your home’s appraised value doesn’t match its contract price? This is a legitimate concern for sellers in our market since so many listings are fetching multiple offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you can do is &lt;strong&gt;have your Realtor check the appraisal for errors&lt;/strong&gt;. Appraisers are super busy right now (along with everyone else), so there might be a typo somewhere in their report that threw everything off. In one of our client’s recent appraisals, for example, the home’s square footage was incorrect. After we identified the error and corrected it, everything was fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If there are no errors in the appraisal, your Realtor can submit a rebuttal&lt;/strong&gt;. In this situation, we’ll pull comparable sales in your neighborhood and show them to the lender. They’ll then decide whether any changes are necessary. This is still a challenge, though, and it doesn’t always work out in favor of the seller. However, it’s still an opportunity to increase the appraisal so that it’s closer to the contract price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Appraisers are super busy right now (along with everyone else), so there might be a typo somewhere in their report that threw everything off.%20http://localhost:4000/when-an-appraisal-contract-price-dont-match.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Appraisers are super busy right now (along with everyone else), so there might be a typo somewhere in their report that threw everything off.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If neither of these options work, your Realtor will have to go back to the drawing board and renegotiate with the buyer’s agent&lt;/strong&gt; to come up with an agreed-upon price. Buyers and sellers understand that the market has been increasing these past few years. If you work with us, we’ll negotiate a win-win price to get you the most money possible for your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/when-an-appraisal-contract-price-dont-match.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/when-an-appraisal-contract-price-dont-match.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Most Common Forms of Property Ownership</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Iq2GU7q3Z3o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;re reviewing the most common forms of property ownership in our area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What are the most common forms of property ownership in Central Florida?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the answer, let’s start with a &lt;strong&gt;quick reminder: Title equals ownership&lt;/strong&gt;. Title can be held in two different ways, the first of which being as “severalty” (meaning it’s owned by an independent person or entity), and the second being as a “concurrent estate” (meaning it’s owned by more than one person at a given time). So, now that we’re clear on those definitions, let’s move on to the two most common forms of ownership for both individual owners and multiparty owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common forms of ownership for an individual in Central Florida are “fee simple” and “leasehold” ownership. &lt;strong&gt;Fee simple ownership is when an individual owns a piece of real estate outright&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning they own all the land, dwelling, and air rights to a property. Fee simple tenure is also considered indefinite, wherein the owner has the right to sell or dispose of the property as they please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leasehold ownership is basically where a parcel of land and the building on that land have different owners&lt;/strong&gt;. So, in essence, the owner of the land is leasing the rights of the property to the tenant. Leasehold ownership is also referred to as “tenancy for years” because it generally lasts for a specific period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Title can be held in two different ways: 'severalty' or 'concurrent estate.'%20http://localhost:4000/the-most-common-forms-of-property-ownership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Title can be held in two different ways: ‘severalty’ or ‘concurrent estate.’”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things get a bit more complicated when two or more owners take title to a single piece of real property. In fact, there are several different kinds of multiparty ownership. The two main types of multiparty ownership in Central Florida are “tenants in common” and “joint tenants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenants in common refers to instances in which each owner retains separate rights over their share of the property&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, let’s say two people own the same commercial building together. The deed specifies that Person A owns 60% and Person B owns 40%. Person A can sell or give away their 60% without telling Person B because the sale would not affect Person B’s ownership of his 40% share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;if these co-owners were joint tenants, then each owner would have equal rights over the entire property&lt;/strong&gt;. In other words, Person A could not sell a share of the property without Person B’s consent. Furthermore, if either co-owner were to die, the survivor would automatically take full possession of the property, a scenario which is also known as “joint tenants with rights of survivorship.” If you’re married, it’s called “tenant by the entireties,” which is basically the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this message helped clarify some property-related jargon you’ve heard being thrown around. If you have any questions about ownership or are interested in soon becoming a property owner yourself, reach out to us by phone or email anytime. We’re always happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-most-common-forms-of-property-ownership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-most-common-forms-of-property-ownership.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
